You can now access Knox E-FOTA firmware management capabilities on Microsoft Intune, giving you flexible control over OS versions and
security updates on your fleet of Samsung devices, right from the Microsoft Intune admin center.
To use Knox E-FOTA, you must first sign up for a Samsung Knox account on samsungknox.com.
When getting started, select "Knox Suite - Enterprise Plan" to get a free trial of our services
then sign up for a Samsung account for Business.
Once you've submitted your Samsung Knox application, inform your Samsung contact to approve your account. When you're approved
for Samsung Knox, you'll receive a confirmation email with your new Knox Customer ID.
The Knox Suite - Enterprise Plan trial license you receive when you create a Samsung Knox account lets you try our services for 90 days
with up to 30 devices. To continue using Knox E-FOTA after that, you'll need to purchase a commercial license from a reseller.
To do this, sign in to your Knox Admin Portal, and go to Licenses
Here, click Actions, and Get a license, where you can find Knox license resellers to purchase a commercial Knox Suite - Enterprise Plan.
When Knox E-FOTA runs on your devices, it prompts your device users to accept the terms and conditions, and the privacy policy. You can
configure Knox E-FOTA to skip this step so it can set up on your devices without device user interaction. To do this, click your account icon
on the Knox Admin Portal, then click Settings. Scroll down to Knox E-FOTA and click Privacy policy.
Then, check "Skip Knox E-FOTA Terms and Conditions and Privacy Policy", and click SAVE.
Now you can connect Microsoft Intune with "Knox E-FOTA". To do this, sign in to your Microsoft Intune admin center, and go to
"Tenant administration", then "Connectors and tokens"
Under "Connectors and tokens", go to "Firmware over-the-air update", and select Samsung on the list of OEMs.
Click "Connect", and sign in to your Samsung Knox account.
On the "Access requested" page, review the access permissions you're granting for Microsoft Intune, then click "Allow".
The Samsung Firmware over-the-air connector status shows that you're connected.
If you were previously using Knox E-FOTA on the Knox Admin Portal, note that connecting Microsoft Intune to Knox E-FOTA disables the
EMM groups feature in your Knox Admin Portal, and any devices that were previously added to Knox E-FOTA from an EMM group sync need to
be added again by registering them on Microsoft Intune.
Also, Microsoft Intune only displays Android FOTA deployments that were created from its own console. When you assign a deployment to
your devices, it overwrites any existing campaigns previously assigned to those devices.
Now you can create a device group for the Samsung devices you want to manage.
In the Microsoft Intune admin center, go to "Groups" and create a new group. Give it a name and click "Create"
Give it a name and click "Create".
Next, deploy the required Samsung apps. You'll need both Knox E-FOTA and Knox Service Plugin installed on your devices.
Go to "Apps"
then "Android", and click "Create"
Select "Store app" and "Managed Google Play app" as the app type.
Search for "Knox E-FOTA" and add it
then search for "Knox Service Plugin" and add that as well.
Then assign both apps to your device group.
Select the app
and click Properties
Edit the assignments
and add your device group.
Repeat those steps for Knox Service Plugin as well.
Now configure Knox Service Plugin to automatically install and launch the Knox E-FOTA app.
Go to "Devices" then "Configuration", and create a new policy.
Select "Android Enterprise" as the platform, then "OEMConfig" as the profile type.
Choose Knox Service Plugin
and under "Device-wide policies", enable device policy controls.
Then configure the "Firmware update policy"
enable firmware controls and enable E-FOTA client installation and launch.
Assign this profile to your device group and create the policy.
If you haven't already, enroll your Samsung devices on Microsoft Intune as company devices, and add them to your device group.
Go to "Groups"
select your device group
click "Members", and add the devices you want to manage.
Once your devices are ready, register them with Samsung Knox E-FOTA. Go to "Tenant administration" then "Connectors and tokens",
and select "Firmware over-the-air update".
Choose Samsung from the OEM list
and under "Register Devices with Samsung", click "Add groups".
Select your device group and click "Register".
You can check the status of device registration on the Monitor tab.
Now you can create your firmware deployment. Go to "Devices"
then "Android FOTA deployments", and click "Create".
Select Samsung as the manufacturer
give your deployment a name, and configure your deployment settings.
Select the device models, sales codes, and CSCs you want to target. Then choose your "Update type".
"Latest any" automatically pushes the newest available version to your devices
while "Latest Up To Max OS Version" limits it to a specific OS version.
"Lock current firmware version" maintains the current firmware on your devices
and "Select firmware version" lets you pick a specific version available to your targeted devices.
You can set the date range when devices can perform firmware updates, and set installation and download time windows to control when
during the day devices can begin downloading and installing firmware, based on the device's local timezone.
You can also set how many times device users are allowed to postpone a firmware update
and how often they're reminded of a pending
firmware update.
You can also set device conditions needed for firmware installation.
Require a minimum battery level before installation begins, require devices to be charging, or only perform firmware downloads
over certain network types.
Once you've configured all your settings, assign the deployment to your device groups and click "Create".
Your Samsung devices will now receive firmware updates according to the policy you've configured. You can monitor deployment status
and device compliance from the Android FOTA deployments page in the Microsoft Intune admin center.
To learn more about using Knox E-FOTA on the Microsoft Intune admin center, see our documentation at docs.samsungknox.com.
Thanks for watching!